<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quanteda Initiative</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Quanteda Initiative</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quanteda article published in the Journal of Open Source Software</title>
      <link>/news/joss-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/joss-paper/</guid>
      <description>The Quanteda team has published a paper in the Journal of Open Source Software. The journal publishes peer-reviewed articles on research software packages, aiming to improve the quality of the software submitted.
The paper summarizes the design and functions of Quanteda, focusing on corpus management, natural langauge processing, text scaling and text statistics, and visualization.
If you use the Quanteda package in your own work, please cite this paper in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text analysis workshop at BIGSSS &amp; SOCIUM in Bremen</title>
      <link>/news/workshop-at-bigsss-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/workshop-at-bigsss-2018/</guid>
      <description>Kenneth Benoit and Stefan Müller will hold a two-day workshop on text-as-data approaches and the quanteda package on 22-23 November 2018 in Bremen. The event is organized by the Bremen International Graduate School of Social Sciences (BIGSSS) and SOCIUM.
Kenneth Benoit will give a keynote speech on &amp;ldquo;Recent Advances in Quantitative Text Analysis&amp;rdquo;. Afterwards, Stefan Müller will conduct training sessions on topics such as importing textual data, tokenization, dictionary approaches, supervised and unsupervised learning, and topic modelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quanteda presentation at Tokyo R meeting</title>
      <link>/news/tokyo-r-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/tokyo-r-2018/</guid>
      <description>At a meeting of Tokyo R on 15 June 2018 at Yahoo Japan&amp;rsquo;s headquarters, Kohei Watanabe presented an overview of quantitative text analysis and how to implement it using the latest version of quanteda. The event was attended by more than 200 international delegates, including staff from R Studio. We thank the organizers for giving us such a great opportunity to publicize our activities and software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text analysis workshop at WZB Berlin</title>
      <link>/news/workshop-at-wzb-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/workshop-at-wzb-2018/</guid>
      <description>Kohei Watanabe and Stefan Müller held a workshop on quanteda on 31 January 2018, the day before the Manifesto Corpus Conference 2018 held from 1-2 February 2018 at the WZB Berlin Social Science Center. This event featured the newly launched new tutorial website that contains a step-by-step introduction to quantitative text analysis using quanteda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quanteda v1.0 launch at LondonR event</title>
      <link>/news/london-r-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/london-r-2018/</guid>
      <description>At a meeting of London R meeting on 16 January 2018, we announced the release of quanteda v1.0. See the presentation here. We thank all the participants and organizers for the great opportunity and the excellent turnout.
A video of the presentation is available on the YouTube channel of the Quanteda Initiative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text analysis workshop at ESSSC</title>
      <link>/news/workshop-at-esssc-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/workshop-at-esssc-2017/</guid>
      <description>We will convene a half-day workshop at European Symposium Series on Societal Challenges in Computational Social Science on quantitative text analysis using quanteda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Based in London, the Quanteda Initiative is a UK non-profit organization devoted to the promotion of open-source text analysis software. It supports active development of these tools, in addition to providing training materials, training events, and sponsoring workshops and conferences. Its main product is the open-source quanteda package for R, but the Quanteda Initiative also supports a family of independent but interrelated packages for providing additional functionality for natural language processing and document management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/</guid>
      <description>Kenneth Benoit Managing Director and Founder  I&#39;m also a Professor in the Department of Methodology, London School of Economics and Political Science. I&#39;m a social scientist, software developer, and amateur photographer.     Kohei Watanabe Chief Technology Officer and Director  I am also an Assistant Professor at Waseda University (Tokyo). I design and write core functions of quanteda and oversee development of other packages for text analysis to make quantitative text analysis more accessible to people from different backgrounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>quanteda  quanteda is an R package providing comprehensive functionality for managing and analyzing textual data.
    readtext  readtext is a one-function R package that reads and converts files containing text from a variety of input formats.
    spacyr  spacyr is an R wrapper to the spaCy “industrial strength natural language processing” Python library.
    stopwords  stopwords provids “one-stop shopping” for stopword lists in R, for multiple languages from many sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/</guid>
      <description>Part of the Quanteda Initiative is to promote the use of the tools whose development it supports through training and dissemination activities. These include publicly accessible workshops, invitation-only conferences, and bespoke training events.
For a list of upcoming events, see the Events category in our News section.
To arrange training in the use of quanteda or in quantitative text analysis methodology more broadly, email us at admin@quanteda.org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quanteda</title>
      <link>/quanteda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quanteda/</guid>
      <description> Documentation  Detailed online documentation and examples
    Tutorials  Step-by-step tutorials for using quanteda
    Publications  Research papers written using quanteda
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>readtext</title>
      <link>/readtext/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/readtext/</guid>
      <description> Heading 3 Some texts.
Heading 4 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>